kcm.org 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy | Kenneth Copeland Ministries

**YOUR PRIVACY IS OUR CONCERN.**

The protection of your privacy is very important to us here at Kenneth Copeland Ministries. We value your trust, and want you to understand what information we collect, how we protect it, and how it is used. Personal information—nonpublic information that identifies you—is essential to Kenneth Copeland Ministries in meeting its goal to provide you with our ministry, services, and ministry-related products and so it will be treated with respect and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Any reference to “Kenneth Copeland Ministries” or “KCM” within the context of this Privacy Policy is intended, and shall be considered to be inclusive of each and all entities operated by Kenneth Copeland Ministries, including its International Offices.

 **SECTION 1 – WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?**

When you purchase something from our site, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us such as your name, address and email address. This enables us to both fulfill and support the products you purchase.

When you browse our site, we also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system so we can better improve the experience for all our users.

Email marketing: With your permission, we may send you emails about new products, free and premium content (like blog posts, content articles, YouTube videos, free product offers, live event alerts, etc.), and special announcements.

Mobile: When you download or use apps created by Kenneth Copeland Ministries or our subsidiaries, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. We may use this information to provide you with personalized content and location based interactions. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services. For more information about how to do this, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer.

 **SECTION 2 – CONSENT**

When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason (i.e.  Daily devotional emails, newsletter subscription and announcements), we will ask you directly for your expressed consent and provide you with an opportunity to withdraw your consent.

You may withdraw your consent at any time by clicking on an “unsubscribe” link which is offered at the bottom of every email we send.

You may also withdraw your consent anytime, by contacting us here or mailing us at: Kenneth Copeland Ministries, P.O. Box 961010, Fort Worth, TX 76161-9975.

 **SECTION 3 – DISCLOSURE**

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law to do so or if you violate our Terms of Service. 

IMPORTANT: We do not sell, rent or otherwise disclose your personal information to any third parties, including but not limited to advertisers, strategic partners or vendors. Again, we take your privacy very seriously.

 **SECTION 4 – DATA STORAGE**

Our shopping cart solution is DonorDirect, it’s hosted and managed by KCM. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you.

Your data is stored through KCM’s data storage, databases and the general DonorDirect application. KCM stores your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

Payment:

If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Bluefin/PayConex stores your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted.

All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.

NOTE: At no point during the transaction does Kenneth Copeland Ministries take custody or store your credit card information. This is process is monitored and managed by Bluefin/PayConex, and you can read their terms of service, privacy policy and PCI Compliance information by visiting their site at: <https://www.bluefin.com/privacy-policy>

 **SECTION 5 – THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

Links: When you click on links on our store or site, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

 **SECTION 6 – SECURITY**

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

 **SECTION 7 – COOKIES**

Kenneth Copeland Ministries utilizes cookies to create a more customized experience for our users and customers. For example, we use a login cookie so members do not have to re-enter their username and password each time they return to our site. We also use tracking pixels (i.e. Google Analytics) to aid in measuring and tracking where our website traffic is coming from and to track the performance of our site. Finally, we use remarking pixels from Facebook and Google to aid in customized, targeted followup advertising.

 **SECTION 8 – AGE OF CONSENT**

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.

 **SECTION 9 – CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

 **QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you would like to: access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information, please contact us.

 **For terms of use** ,  **please click here.**

Any rights not expressly granted herein are reserved.
